Preliminary Guide to the William M. Piatt Papers, 1843-1908 (bulk 1845-1883)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William M. Piatt papers 1843-1908 (bulk 1845-1883)
Piatt, William M.
Extent: 593 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01039
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William M. Piatt Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1958. Additions were received in 2008 and 2009.
Biographical Note
Lawyer and state legislator of Tunkhannock and Harrisburg, Pa.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises letters to and from Piatt. Topics include Pennsylvania canals; Democratic Party politics in Pennsylvania in the 1840s, 1850s, and 1860s; the temperance movement; the Piatt family, Pennsylvania railroads; the Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention of 1872; and the Liberal Republican Party.
Addition (2008-0297) (10 items; 0.1 lin. ft., 1853-1908) includes letters to and from William Piatt, along with two later letters from his sons. This addition has been interfiled with the collection.
Addition (2009-0239) (63 items; 0.2 lin. ft., 1846-1873 and undated) comprises letters to and from William Piatt. Most are from family members. This addition has been interfiled with the collection.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Piatt, William M.; Piatt family; Pyatte family; Democratic Party (Pa.).; Liberal Republican Party; Pennsylvania. Constitutional Convention (1872-1873).; Canals -- Pennsylvania; Railroads -- Pennsylvania; Temperance; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government
Contents of Collection
- William Piatt Papers (Accessions 1956-0647, 1956-0737, 1960-0135, 2008-0297, and 2009-0239)
  - Letters, 1860-1864 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1864-1868 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1868-1908 and undated (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers and Printed Material, 1854-1925 (Box 1)
  - Bills, Receipts, etc., 1848-1856 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1856 January - February (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1856 February - October (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1856 October - 1859 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1843-1852 (Box 2)
  - Letters, 1853-1855 (Box 2)
  - Letters, 1860-1896 and undated (Box 2)